《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously on "Arrow"...
[咒语]
Kanjigar septum vohnostrum.
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
达克先生收押不能保释
Mr. Darhk will be held without bail
且不能获释
or possibility of release.
翻译：SophiaSaaaga  木浅薰  PiPi  Reginamoon
■
你现在可以致电你的组织
You may now call your organization
把另一条信息传递出去
and have that other message delivered.
他说你是他最后的王牌
He said you were his ace in the hole.
翻译：Dzysteven  Michael  Z小花儿  肉松   细小小
你想让我这么称呼你吗
Is that what you'd like me to call you...
校对：Z小花儿  Michael  Reginamoon  迷失星城
或者你更喜欢被称做狄格尔先生
or do you prefer Mr. Diggle?
精校：陈小圈
时间轴 ：风吹来的那片云
特效&后期 ：咖啡Lee     总监：苹果果
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
安迪
Andy.
这黑漆漆的  你在做什么呢老弟
What are you doing in the dark, man?
我不想吵醒莎拉
Didn't want to wake Sara up.
谢谢你告诉我这东西在哪里
Thanks for letting me know where this was.
我希望你有安全感
I want you to feel safe.
你在电话上听起来挺慌张的
You sounded pretty rattled on the phone.
到底发生了什么
What the hell's going on?
蜂巢知道我还活着  约翰
HIVE knows I'm alive, John.
他们找你麻烦了吗
Did they come after you?
算是吧  派了个人来找我
In a way. I mean, one of them reached out,
那人牙口不错  缺了只手
some guy with perfect teeth and a missing hand.
我不...他没告诉我他叫什么
I didn't--he didn't tell me his name.
马尔科姆·梅林
Malcolm Merlyn.
那个刺客联盟的首领
The head of the League of Assassins?
现在不是了
Well, not anymore.
对  现在他跟达米恩·达克一伙
Yeah. Well, now he works with Damien Darhk.
什么时候的事
Since when?
两天前
Two nights ago.
安迪  你应该早点告诉我的
Andy, you should have told me this earlier.
我知道  我很抱歉
I know, man, and I'm sorry,
但整件事都太突然了
But this whole thing has got me thrown, man.
我以为蜂巢不知道我在哪
I didn't think HIVE knew where I was.
梅林想干什么
What did Merlyn want?
我觉得蜂巢和达克之间
I think there's some kind of friction going on
可能有些不合
between HIVE and Darhk.
你难道没发现他们甚至没有尝试
Have you noticed they haven't even tried
把达克救出监狱
to bust Darhk out of prison?
是啊  我也一直在琢磨这事
Yeah, I've been thinking about that.
现在这个梅林叫我帮他
And now this Merlyn guy asks me to help him.
帮他干什么  把达克救出铁山监狱吗
Help him what, bust Darhk out of Iron Heights?
明晚11点  国防部将在
DOD's scheduled to run Paveway Missiles
佩尼镇发射铺路导弹
through Pennytown tomorrow night at 23:00.
梅林想让我帮他劫下导弹
Merlyn wants me to help him hijack the shipment.
是吗  只需一枚铺路导弹
Yeah? Well, just one of those Paveways makes
就再也不用担心进监狱了
for a pretty good get out of jail free card.
所以我才来问你
And that's why I'm asking you, man.
我该怎么办
What do I do?
先是绑架  再是偷导弹
First, kidnapping, then stealing missiles.
梅林为了跟达克交朋友  还真是拼
Merlyn's trying really hard to be friends with Darhk.
马尔科姆相信达克赢定了
Malcolm's convinced Darhk is on the winning side.
他甚至想保护我不被达克的计划牵连
He's even trying to protect me from whatever he's planning.
达克唯一该计划的
The only thing Darhk should be planning on
就是被判有罪
is getting convicted at trial.
为什么我觉得这东西很吓人
Why does that thing creep me out the way it does?
因为它确实吓人
Because it's creepy.
有件事我一直没告诉你们
There's something that I haven't told you guys.
我好震惊
Shocker.
抱歉
Sorry.
我以前见过这神像
I've seen this idol before.
什么  在哪儿
What? Where?
炼狱
Lian yu.
你还真是不爱谈论那地方  是吧
You really love not talking about that place, don't you?
安保系统升级得怎么样了
Where are we with the security upgrades?
一切就绪  我们可以出发了
Everything's in place. We're good to go.
既然梅林知道这个避难室
Because Merlyn knows the bunker's location.
如果他和达克合作...
If he's working with Darhk--
那我们就得提防
Then that means we have to worry about him
他来这里
coming down here and
偷走这吓人的石像
stealing this creepy stone thingy.
他不是要去劫导弹吗
And what about his plan to hijack the missile shipment?
奥利弗  我觉得应该让安迪按兵不动
Oliver, I think we keep Andy right where he is.
那样我们就有个内应
That way, we have someone on the inside.
你确定这是个好主意吗
Are you sure that's a good idea?
他已经摆脱达克的控制了
Well, he's out from under the influence of Darhk.
我们可以信任他
We can trust him.
信任是一回事
Trust is one thing.
让他当双面间谍  又是一回事
Installing him as a double agent, that's another.
这需要承受巨大的压力
That's a lot of pressure to put on someone,
更何况他还在恢复期
especially someone that is still in recovery.
奥利弗  安迪是个正直的人
Oliver, Andy is a standup guy.
他能行
He's got this.
你收到一条讯息
And you've got this.
事件通知
鲁维·达克提名演讲
你大可不必理会
You could blow that off.
你不欠鲁维·达克什么
You don't owe Ruvé  Darhk anything.
根据传统  失败方要出席胜利方的提名演讲
Tradition. Loser attends the winner's acceptance speech.
你没失败
You didn't lose.
你是因为她丈夫才主动退出的
You pulled out of the race because of her husband.
我会尽力不跟媒体提这事
Which I will try not to mention to the press.
赶紧结束这事吧
Let's get this over with.
在艰苦的努力下我们才走到了今天
We worked hard to get to this moment,
但现在  真正的挑战才刚刚开始
but now the real work begins--
那就是让这座城市重新崛起
to make this city great again.
谢谢
Thank you.
奎恩先生  能回答我几个问题吗
Mr. Queen, have time to answer a few questions?
我不再是候选人了
I'm not a candidate anymore.
我来只是为了表示对新市长的支持
I'm just here to support the new mayor.
所以你不打算回应竞选结果了
So no comment on the write-in results?
什么竞选结果
Qhat write-in results?
48%的选民把票投给了你哥哥
48% of the electorate wrote in your brother's name on their ballots.
对一个放弃竞选的候选者
That's a historic showing for a candidate
这真是前所未有的支持了
who pulled out of the race.
我就不打扰你和前对手叙旧了
I'll let you and your former opponent catch up.
谢谢你今晚能来  奎恩先生
Well, thank you for coming out tonight, Mr. Queen.
这是个很高尚的姿态
It's a very gracious gesture.
城市的利益在我心里永远是第一位
I am always gonna have this city's best interests at heart.
希望你的朋友们也这样想
Well, let's hope the same can be said for your friends.
兰斯小姐  很高兴见到你
Miss Lance, I am so pleased to meet you.
我很佩服你在达米恩·达克的
I was very impressed by your handling
听证会上的表现
of the Damien Darhk hearing.
那只是个热身
I was just getting warmed up.
希望你会忙到没有时间参加庭审
Well, my hope is that you'll be too busy to handle the trial.
地方检察官雷姆兹
District attorney Remz
现在是我的新副市长了
has taken on a new position as my deputy mayor,
我希望你能接任他现在的职位
and I would like you to succeed him as D.A.
考虑一下吧
Think about it.
我觉得假如我俩合作的话
I think that we could do great things
一定能给这个城市做出更多贡献
for this city if we worked together.
保重
Take care.
听着  瑞特的人比我们多
Listen. Reiter's men outnumber us.
我们有枪  但他们也有
We have guns, but so do they,
所以等我们上去
so when we get up there,
绝对不能手软  明白了吗
we cannot hesitate to kill, do you understand?
泰安娜
Taiana?
几个月前  我还只是个潜水教练
Just months ago, I was a dive instructor.
根本想不到我会杀人
Couldn't dream of taking a life.
我做不到
I wouldn't.
这个地方就是地狱
This place truly is hell.
它把我们都变成了魔鬼
It makes monsters of us all.
照片上是谁
Who's in the photo?
我和我弟弟
Me and my brother.
有时候我都忘记了我们曾经这么幸福
I forget sometimes that we were once this happy
这么单纯
and this innocent.
我刚到这里时
When I first got here,
会经常看我过去的一张照片
I used to look at a photo from my past.
开始那段时间还是有用的
It helped for a time,
让我不忘记曾经的我
reminded me of the person that I used to be,
但我得说
but I'm telling you now
那个我在这里绝对活不下去
that that person wouldn't survive here,
如果你也放不下过去  那你也一样
and you won't either if you stay focused on the past.
明白了吗
Do you understand?
明白
Da.
我们怎么干掉那些混蛋
How do I take those bastards out?
跟我走
Follow me.
11:30已经过了
It's past 11:30.
那是美国军队  迟到才正常
It's the U.S. Army, man. Late means on time.
也许是我们守错地方了
Or we're staking out the wrong place.
安迪说了是这里
If Andy says this is where it's gonna be,
那肯定就是这里
this is where it's gonna be.
导弹没有动的痕迹
No movement yet on the missiles.
我们应该跟他们一起去的
Yeah. We should be out there with them.
虽然有约翰超能力联合调查组的好玩意儿
Even with John's fancy A.R.G.U.S. toys,
有我们守着还是更安全些
this place is more secure with us watching over it.
你打算接受吗
So are you gonna do it,
白天做地方检察官
be district attorney by day
晚上做黑金丝雀
and Black Canary by night?
不知道
I don't know.
这确实能更好地盯着邪恶夫人
I mean, it would help having eyes on Mrs. Evil.
如果你相信马尔科姆
Yeah. Well, if you believe Malcolm,
那这工作也不会长久
it will be a short-term job anyway.
等这个城市毁了
Won't be any need for a D.A.
也就不需要地方检察官了
once the city's destroyed.
你不管他叫爸爸了
You stopped calling him dad.
因为他不配当我爸爸
Well, that's because he's not dad.
我知道我以前也这么说过
Look. I know I've said that before,
但这次不一样
but this time, it's different.
这次我们两个都这么认为
This time, it's mutual.
这话简直是荒谬到极致了  亲爱的
That couldn't be further from the truth, dear.
顺说狄格尔先生的升级版安保措施需要升级了
Mr. Diggle's upgraded security needs a few upgrades by the way.
你知道我们的目的
You know why we're here.
交出神像
Hand over the idol,
就不会有什么麻烦
and there won't be any trouble.
那看来是要有麻烦了
Well, there's gonna be trouble then.
安  迪
东西上路了
好的  信号来了
All right. That's the signal.
那人穿得很像刺客联盟的人
Guy's dressed like a league of assassins.
梅林可能还有一些忠诚的跟随者
Merlyn probably has a few loyalists left.
带我就位
Get me in position.
不要  不要  等一下
No, no, no, no! Hold on!
是我  是我  是我
It's me, it's me, it's me!
你一直都这么悄然无声的吗
Are you always this quiet?
别这样  我们刚救下这批货
Come on. We just saved the shipment,
你弄得好像很容易一样
and you made it look easy.
因为本来就很容易
That's because it was easy.
那个神像
The idol.
不见了
It's gone.
绿   箭
第四季  第十八集
你俩不用这么警戒了
You two can stand down.
他走了
He's gone.
-梅林  -对
- Merlyn? - Yeah.
还有一些刺客联盟的成员
And a few League of Assassin members.
他拿走了神像  我本该阻止他的
He took the idol. I should have stopped him.
我们本该在这里的
We should have been here.
我们...  我相信你已经竭尽全力了
We... I'm sure you did everything you could.
梅林会把神像给他的新朋友达克
Merlyn's gonna give that idol to his new friend Darhk
这样他的魔法就回来了
to get his mojo back.
我们搜查了监控视频
We've been scouring the streetcams.
就好像他消失了一样
It's like he just vanished.
这就是为什么联盟叫他魔术师
That's why the League calls him the Magician.
我去街上看看
I'm gonna go hit the streets.
西娅  没人会供出梅林的
Thea, no one is gonna give up Merlyn.
那我就去街上痛扁几个人
Well, then I'm gonna hit people on the streets.
我去问问安迪
I'll check with Andy,
看看他能不能找出梅林在哪
see if he can get a twenty on Merlyn.
约翰
John.
安迪已经冒了很大风险
Andy has already risked a lot.
我不想暴露他的身份
I don't want to put him in a compromised position.
奥利弗  他已经暴露了
Oliver, he's already in a compromised position.
他跟我们要找的人有直接关联
There's a direct line between him and the man we are looking for.
我们该好好利用他
Let's use that.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
你有什么想法
Talk to me.
这次导弹任务过于简单了
This missile job was too easy.
感觉就像梅林的手下根本没有尽力
It was like Merlyn's men weren't even trying.
但同时这分散了我们的注意
Meanwhile, it pulled our focus,
让梅林能来到这里
Merlyn was able to come down here
拿到他想要的
and get exactly what he wanted.
你觉得梅林耍了安迪吗
You think Merlyn played Andy?
万一是安迪在耍我们呢
What if Andy is playing us?
听着  我不是说这不可能
Look. I'm not saying it's not possible,
但我们现在说的是约翰的弟弟
but this is John's brother we're talking about.
他已经为我们做了那么多
I mean, he's done so much for us.
他  他还救了莱拉
He-- he saved Lyla.
那我就该完全信任他吗
Should I just trust him outright?
不  但你最好搞状况之后再指责他
No, but you better be sure before making an accusation
否则你和约翰的关系就不可弥补了
that you and John can't recover from.
是我爸  我得接一下
It's my dad. I have to take this.
救命  救命  救命
Help me! Help me! Help me!
求求你了  救救我
Please. You have to help me!
这是怎么了  怎么回事
What is it? What's going on?
康克林  或者说他的附体
Conklin, or what remains of him,
那东西杀了那些人
the thing that killed those men,
杀了奥利弗
it killed Oliver.
它把瑞特困在了下面
It has Reiter trapped down there.
快走
Come on!
请问你们还需要什么吗
不用了  谢谢
别这么看我
Don't be too impressed.
我就从莎拉那学了这么一句中文
That's the only Chinese I was able to pick up from Sara.
听着  你想好
So listen. You thought about how you're
怎么跟新上任的市长说
gonna tell our newly elected mayor
你要拒绝她给的工作了吗
that you're turning down her job offer?
我想好了
I have,
但我不确定要这么做
but I'm not sure that I will.
她可是个疯子  宝贝
Well, this one's a no-brainer, sweetie.
你不能去为一个杀人犯做事
You can't go work for a murderer.
这份工作能让我打入内部
This job would put me in the inner circle.
是  代价就是不能当黑金丝雀
Yeah, at the cost of being the Black Canary.
听着  自从蜂巢杀了地方检察官布雷
Look. Ever since HIVE had D.A. Bray killed,
地方检察官就有全天候安保
the district attorney has 24/7 protection.
他们不会让你离开他们的视线
They would not let you out of their sight.
我会免除安保的
I'll waive it.
你觉得瑞文·达克会同意吗
You think Ruve Darhk will let that happen?
听着  我没想过我会这么说
Listen. I--I never thought I'd say this,
但我很高兴你是黑金丝雀
but I am glad that you are the Black Canary,
我很高兴你做这些善事
I'm glad for all the good you're doing,
我也很高兴看到这些对你的影响
and I'm glad for the good it's done you.
但你要明白  接受了这份工作
But you got to know that taking this job,
你就要永远摘下面具了
that means taking off that mask forever.
小心  你会伤到自己的
Careful. Could hurt yourself with that.
我打算用这个伤的可不是我自己
It's not myself I'm planning on hurting with it.
是安迪  怎么了
Andy. Yeah?
我找到梅林了
I got eyes on Merlyn.
好  你在哪里
OK. Where are you?
我想这是个废旧纸箱厂
In some old box factory, I think.
你确定就是这里吗
You sure this is the place?
对  我很肯定
Yeah. I'm pretty sure.
快  梅林在这边
Come on. Merlyn's this way.
你为什么没让他用无线电给我们带路
Why didn't you have him radio us in?
我让他留下来做支援
I had him stay behind for backup.
梅林
Merlyn!
小心
Look out!
你没事吧
You OK?
还好
Swell.
怎么回事
What happened?
他为我挡了一箭
He took an arrow for me.
让我看看  让我看看
Let me see, let me see.
别担心  兄弟
Don't worry about it, man.
我们每周都在处理这种事
We deal with this kind of stuff every week.
-走  -不不不
- Come on. - No, no, no, no.
你们现在得去铁山监狱
You got to get to Iron Heights now.
如果梅林不在这  那就说明
If Merlyn's not here, then that--
说明他正带着神像赶去那里
that means he's on his way there with the idol.
如果达克拿到了神像
If Darhk gets that idol,
那就没有监狱能困得住他
No prison will be able to hold him.
总有一天  你会告诉我
One of these days, you're gonna tell me
你是如何做到自由进出这里
how you get in and out of here.
魔术师绝不会揭自己的秘
A Magician never reveals his secrets.
那接下来呢  你打算从我耳朵后面
So what next? You gonna make a coin
变枚硬币出来吗
appear from behind my ear?
你跟我提了这么多要求
You know, you're awfully flippant for a man
还这样非常无礼
who's asked a great deal of me.
你到底拿到没有
Do you have it?
或许现在是时候提醒你
Perhaps now's a good time to remind you
我们的条件了
of our terms.
好  你们父女不受创世纪的影响
Yes. You and your daughter get spared from Genesis.
还是这样吗
Is that still the play?
我想你不明白我为此付出的代价
I don't think you appreciate what this cost me.
得了吧  别这么目空一切
come on. Stop being so high-handed.
怎么了
What's wrong?
梅林先生  你知道虔诚神像是什么吗
Mr. Merlyn, do you know what the khushu idol is?
那在古阿拉伯语中是虔诚的意思
Khushu is an old Arabic term for humbleness,
但是  我不会对你虔诚的
suffice it to say, something I wouldn't associate with you.
当最早的天赋法师铸造这些神像时
When the earliest Homo Magi forged these idols,
是按照他们觊觎超能力的
they did so in the image of those
那些人的形象来做的
whose powers they wished to channel,
所以注意细节很有必要
so attention to detail is essential.
但这少了一块
It's missing a piece.
瑞巴维尔石
The Ribalvei Stone.
他们肯定藏在别的地方了
They must have hidden it someplace else.
找出来  不然你们父女
Find it, or Genesis is not
要担心的就不只是创世纪
what you and your daughter have to fear.
好
All right.
你还需要缝几针
You're gonna need a few stitches,
但这个能暂时止住血
but, uh, this should hold for now.
我需要的远不止缝几针
I'm gonna need a whole lot more than a few stitches.
梅林的手下看到我在帮你们了
Merlyn's men saw me fighting for your team.
所以达克现在知道了我在帮你
Darhk's now gonna know that I'm on your side.
我死定了
I'm a dead man.
他不仅会找我的麻烦
I mean, he's just not gonna stop with me.
他还会去找你
He's gonna come for you,
他还会找莱拉和莎拉的麻烦  天呐
He's gonna come for Lyla, Sara. Oh, God.
听着  他不会找任何人的麻烦
Listen. He's not gonna come for anybody.
好吗  他办不到
OK? He can't.
神像在梅林手上
Merlyn has the idol.
他现在可能已经交给他了
Look. He's probably delivering it to him right now.
不  安迪  他没有
No, Andy. No, he doesn't.
-还缺一块  -什么
- There's a piece missing. - What?
我们从神像上拿走了一块藏在其他地方了
We separated a piece of it and put it in another location.
梅林给他的只是一个又大又丑的镇纸
Only thing Merlyn's delivering is a big, ugly paperweight.
达克会找到的  没什么能瞒着他
Darhk will find it. He finds everything.
听着  安迪  听我说
Listen, listen. Andy, listen to me, man.
他不可能找得到
He won't find anything.
是我亲自藏好的
I hid it myself.
约翰
John.
方便说句话吗
Can I speak to you?
这消息需要保密
This information needs to be compartmentalized.
他很害怕
Listen. He's scared, man,
而这很正常
and for good reason.
他有权知道一切尽在我们掌握之中
He's entitled to know that we have the situation under control.
可要掌控局面就需要保守秘密
Well, that control is only as strong as the secret.
知道的人越少越好
The less people who know, the better.
他为了我不顾一切危险
He risked everything, everything for us.
他还为你挡了一箭
He took an arrow for you.
我相信他
He has my trust.
你为什么不信他
Why doesn't he have yours?
如果马尔科姆现在还没把神像给达克
Malcolm's gonna try and get the idol to Darhk
那他也会想尽办法
if he hasn't done it already.
我能以检察官助理的身份进去
I can go there as A.D.A.
把整个囚室搜一遍
and have the entire cellblock searched.
去吧
Do it.
快手  你和斯巴达回到避难室
Speedy, you and Spartan go back to the bunker,
查监控也好
work CCTV,
用人脸识别也好
work facial recognition,
想方设法
do anything that we can do
找到梅林
to get an eye on Merlyn.
好的
OK.
我能帮上什么忙
And what can I do?
你应该回家休息
You should go home and rest.
你今晚做的已经够多了
You've done enough for tonight.
你呢
What about you?
我也很快就回去  不过要先查条线索
I'll be right behind you. I'm just gonna run down a lead.
你们都回到地面
You guys, get to the surface,
和其他人汇合  然后去找船
gather the others, and go for the boats.
走  快
Go! Come on!
你呢
What about you?
瑞特还在墓穴里
Reiter's still in the catacombs.
如果他找到了神像
If he's found that idol,
你不可能阻止他
you won't be able to stop him.
我们不需要阻止他
We don't need to stop him.
我们困住他就行
We need to trap him.
你们在这儿做得非常好
You guys are doing a wonderful job in there.
我一直打算亲自把这里重新装修一遍
You know, I have been meaning to redecorate the place myself.
我收到了匿名举报说
You know, my office received an anonymous tip
有人把违禁品带了进来
that contraband intended for your use
想要给你使用
was smuggled into this prison.
有什么发现吗
Find anything?
好吧  把这层的每间牢房都搜一遍
All right. Search every cell on this tier.
确保他的朋友们
I want to make sure none of his friends
没有为他藏什么东西
are stashing anything for him.
你应该庆幸
You know, you're lucky
我不是你以为的那种人  兰斯小姐
I'm not the man that you think I am, Miss Lance.
如果我真的是你父亲强烈指控的那种人
If I were the man that your father so vehemently claims,
你现在早就麻烦缠身了  不是吗
you'd be in a lot of trouble right now, wouldn't you?
你是在威胁副检察官吗
Are you threatening an assistant district attorney?
不  不  完全不是
Oh, no, no, no. Not at all.
我只是想知道
Just merely trying to figure out
你父亲怎么会有如此邪恶的想法
where your father gets these vicious ideas from.
我希望他精神还正常
I hope his mind isn't starting to go.
你知道的  有时候长期酗酒
You know, dementia is sometimes
会导致痴呆的
an aftereffect of long-term alcoholism.
你这个混蛋
You're a son of a bitch.
无论如何  他的心脏还正常跳动着
Regardless, it's comforting to know
这点还是很令人欣慰的
that his heart is in the right place.
父亲总会拼尽全力保护女儿
A father would do anything to protect his daughter
远离邪恶[音同”达克"]
from the dark.
我们法庭见吧
I'll see you in court.
你在找什么吗
Looking for something?
天呐
Jeez, man!
你不会敲门吗
Do you know how to knock?
找到梅林了吗
Any luck finding Merlyn?
没有  但我想你早就知道了
No, but I think you already knew that.
我再问你一遍
I'm gonna ask you again.
你在找什么
What are you looking for?
监控  好吧  听着
Surveillance. OK. Look.
蜂巢知道我是约翰的弟弟
HIVE knows I'm John's brother.
他们可能在这里藏了窃听器
They could have hidden bugs here.
也许就是因此你那个独臂朋友
Maybe that's how that one-handed friend of yours
最初才能找到我
found me in the first place.
你总是能找到借口
You always have an answer for everything.
你说什么呢
Hey. What are you talking about?
我觉得你从一开始就是达克的同伙
I think that you've been working with Darhk since the beginning,
你和梅林一直都在耍我们
that you and Merlyn have been playing us this entire time,
你现在跑来这里找神像缺失的那块东西
and now you're here, looking for the missing piece of the idol!
我是你这边的  还记得吗
I'm on your side, remember?
为了保护你  我甚至都受伤了
I even got hurt trying to protect you.
我记得
I remember.
我让约翰相信你
I told John to trust you,
再给你一次机会
to give you another chance,
但我错了
but I was wrong.
因为像你这样的人不会改变
Because men like you don't change.
现在  告诉我
Now you tell me
达克到底在计划什么
What does Darhk have planned?
如果我真是你以为的那种人
If I'm the man that you think I am,
那你该知道严刑拷打也套不出我的话
then you know torture is not gonna get me to say anything.
我还没开始严刑拷打呢
I haven't started torturing you yet.
你在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
让你看看他的真面目
Showing you who he really is!
-告诉他  -约翰  他觉得我是叛徒
- Tell him! - John, he thinks I'm a traitor!
防弹衣也保护不了你的
I know exactly what that kevlar won't protect.
放开他
Let him go.
狄格  你不能相信他
Dig, you can't trust him.
-出去  -约翰
- Get out. - John.
快走
Now.
你没权这么做
You had no right!
我有权
I had every right.
这事关我们的安全
This is about keeping us safe.
不  根本不是  奥利弗
No, it's not, Oliver.
这事关你要掌控你周围的一切
This is about you controlling everything and everyone around you.
劫持导弹一事是安迪给我们通风报信的
Andy tipped us off to the missile heist.
我们前脚去那里
We go there,
梅林后脚就来这里
Merlyn comes here
抢走了神像
and takes the idol.
然后他带我们到梅林的藏身处
Then he brings us to Merlyn's hideout,
在那里我们又遇到了埋伏
where we are met with an ambush.
他还为你挡了一箭
Where he took an arrow for you.
那可能是早就设计好的
That could have been a feint.
当我去你家里质问他的时候
When I confronted him at your apartment,
他正在把整个公寓翻个底朝天
he was tearing it apart.
他是在找监听设备
Looking for surveillance.
或者他是在找神像缺失的那一部分
Or he was looking for the last piece of the idol.
约翰  是你一直和我说
John, you are the one who always tells me
当事情涉及到家人的时候
do not have a blind spot
千万不能盲目
when it comes to your family.
也是你叫我再给安迪一次机会的
And you're the one who told me to give Andy a second chance.
是你想让他从蜂巢中脱离出来
You're the one who wanted to extract him from HIVE.
是你说他可以从黑暗中走出来
You're the one who said he could come back from the darkness
就如同你当初一样
the same way you did.
但我没走出来
But I didn't.
我尝试过
I've tried.
我比以往任何时候都更努力地尝试过了
I've tried harder at this than I ever have at anything,
但最终
but at the end of the day,
我依然是那五年时光所造就的那个人
I am who those 5 years away turned me into,
我依然是他们所造就的那个人
I'm what they turned me into.
那又怎么样  奥利弗
So what, Oliver,
就因为费利西蒂离开了你
just because Felicity left you,
我就应该相信
I'm supposed to believe that
所有人都没有能力获得救赎了吗
all men are incapable of redemption?
并不是所有人都像你一样  奥利弗
Not all men are like you, Oliver.
我们中有些人变了  有些人成长了
Some of us change, some of us grow,
有些人进步了
some of us evolve.
你却在原地踏步  哥们
You are stuck, man,
在自怨自艾和自以为是中原地踏步
stuck in your self-pity and your self-righteousness,
而那才是费利西蒂离开你的原因
and that is why Felicity left you.
我弟弟怎么样是我的事情
My brother is my business.
你不知道他经历了什么
You have no idea what he's been through,
所以你根本没有权利去评论他
and you sure as hell had no right to judge him.
我确信他不是那个意思  奥利
I'm sure he didn't mean that, Ollie.
不  他就是那个意思
Yes, he did.
铁山监狱那边有什么收获
How'd it go in Iron Heights?
搜出来一些一次性手机
Turned up a few burner cell phones,
6袋海洛因  没发现神像
6 bags of heroin, and no idol.
我们黑进了监狱的安保系统
we hacked into the security system at the prison,
所以如果有事情发生
so if anything happens,
我们都能看到
we'll see it.
好的
Right.
你还好吗
Are you ok?
约翰和我起了点争执
John and I had a difference of opinion.
是关于安迪吗
About Andy?
我去质问安迪
I confronted Andy,
然后狄格进来了
and Dig walked in.
也许我应该听从你的建议
Probably should have taken your advice,
地方检察官兰斯
District Attorney Lance.
我目前还只是助理地方检察官
I'm still just an A.D.A.
我准备拒绝这次升迁
I'm turning down the promotion.
因为这是鲁维·达克提出来的吗
Because it's being offered by Ruvé Darhk?
不  是因为接受这个职位
No, because taking the job
意味着放弃和你还有整个团队在这里共事的机会
means giving up my place here with you and the team.
团队都支离破碎了
The team's falling apart.
约翰很生我的气
John's furious with me,
西娅被她对马尔科姆的愤怒所吞噬
Thea's consumed with a rage for Malcolm,
而且
and...
费利西蒂也离开了
Well, Felicity's gone.
成为地方检察官
Becoming district attorney's something
是你这三年兢兢业业努力工作的目标
that you've worked the better part of 3 years for.
我曾经也许是想成为地方检察官
I might have wanted to be D.A.,
但那是很久之前的事了
but that was a lifetime ago.
像莎拉离开的那么久吗
Sara's lifetime?
你化悲痛为力量成为了黑金丝雀
You channeled your grief and became the Black Canary,
但现在莎拉并没有死
but Sara's not dead anymore.
也许你欠自己一个
Maybe you owe it to yourself
回归你之前追寻的梦想的机会
to pursue the path you were on.
你是认真的吗
You're serious?
这个城市已经有足够多戴面具的英雄了
This city has enough heroes with masks on.
现在鲁维·达克当上了市长
With Ruvé Darhk as mayor,
这里需要一位不戴面具的英雄
it needs a hero without a mask.
城市需要劳蕾尔·兰斯
It needs Laurel Lance.
读书时间  20分钟
Read time, 20 minutes.
20分钟
20 minutes.
你对大地有所了解吗
Uh, are you in touch with the land,
有花时间和自然母亲交流吗
spend much time in mother nature?
没有吗  你的祖先有
No? Well, your ancestors did.
他们知道生命是由一系列阶段组成的
They knew that life is a series of phases.
"出生之时  死亡之时
"A time to be born, a time to die,
播种之时  铲除之时
a time to plant, a time to uproot,
杀戮之时"
a time to kill."
用变化应对矛盾的改变
Master the paradox of change with inconstancy,
那么大自然的原始力量
and the primordial force of nature itself
就会任凭你使用了
will be at your beck and call.
我的偶像  尤利乌斯·凯撒
My idol-- Julius Caesar.
"高喊破坏  让那些战争的懦夫逃走吧"
"Cry havoc! And let slip the dogs of war."
「莎士比亚 《凯撒大帝》」
发生什么了
What happened?
当时是休息时间
It was rec hour.
犯人从牢房里出来了
The prisoners were out of their cells.
他现在挟持了狱警
He's holding the guards hostage.
-多少人  -多少人不重要
- How many? - Doesn't matter how many.
重要的是要把达克关回去
We have to put Darhk back in his cage.
穿上装备
Let's gear up!
奥利弗  只有先抓住她
Oliver, I can't prosecute him
我才能起诉他
without getting him into custody first.
最后一次
One last time.
铁山联邦监狱
这里到底怎么回事
What the hell's going on around here?
不能就这么傻站着等着出事吧
Can't just stand around here waiting for something to happen.
这里谁负责
Who's in charge?
不是你  队长  你被停职了
Not you, Captain. You've been suspended.
你是派克  对吧
Pike, right?
这就对了
Well, that figures.
就这么等着
Wait it out till we've got a stack
最后只剩下一堆死人
of dead bodies on our hands.
抱歉  长官  请回到你的车上
I'm sorry, sir. You need to get back to your vehicle.
不  我要跟他说话
No. I want to speak with him.
我要马上跟他说话
I need to speak with him now!
-我做不到  -不  你做得到
- I can't do that. - Yes, you can do that.
你做得到  去给我...  算了
You can do that. Go get... never mind.
-我看见他了  -长官
- I see him. - Sir!
派克  我看见你在那了
Pike! I see you overhere!
我们怎么才能避开这些警察
How are we gonna get through all those cops?
兰斯好像帮我们做到了
Looks like Lance has it covered.
显然痛揍了派克副队长一顿
By laying into Lieutenant Pike apparently.
还把他打倒了
And he just knocked him out.
这就给我们留出了空档
As a distraction to give us an opening.
行动
Let's move.
我不是让你自己来吗
Thought I told you to come alone.
你是说了  但我不照做
You did, and I didn't.
我知道你不相信我
Look. I know you don't trust me,
这就是我来的原因  向你证明
But that's why I'm here-- to prove you can.
达克在餐厅里挟持了人质
Darhk has hostages in the mess hall.
我们分散开  从各个方向包围他
Let's fan out and hit them from all sides.
我记得这个人
I remember this guy.
他的嘴唇
Those lips.
好恶心
Gross.
热身做得不错
Not a bad warmup.
看来你已经准备好再比一次了
It seems like you're ready for a rematch.
去找其他人
Go get the others.
我来搞定他
I've got this.
-不  让我来  -快去
- No. Let me take him. - Go!
看看我把你教得怎么样
Let's see how well I taught you.
我跟警察说如果他们靠近监狱
You know, the police took me seriously
我就会开始杀人质
when I said I would start killing hostages
他们很听话
if they moved upon the prison.
可惜那些戴面具的治安维持者
It's too bad our masked vigilante friends
没收到这消息
didn't get the memo.
所以你真的很不幸
Well, too bad for you really.
杀了他
Kill them.
你已经没有杀人的欲望了  我能看出来
You no longer have the drive to kill, and it shows.
你不再嗜血  可你也丢掉了部分自我
You lost part of yourself when they cured you of that bloodlust,
这就是你永远无法打败我的原因
and that is why you will never beat me.
安德鲁·狄格尔  好久不见
Andrew Diggle, it's been a while.
放开他
Let him go!
把枪放下
Drop your weapons.
不要
Don't do it.
你随便  但当我数到三的时候
Suit yourself, but on the count of 3,
我会让他的脑浆喷到墙上
I'm gonna turn that wall into
就像杰克逊·波洛克[美国画家]的画一样
a Jackson Pollock painting with his brains.
一
1...
二
2...
好吧
OK.
也不是那么难吧
Now was that so hard?
我想你有东西要给我
I believe you have something for me.
安迪
Andy.
对不起了  兄弟
I'm sorry, man.
安迪
Andy.
我已经追踪你们的踪迹好几个月了
I've been tracking your movements for months.
我知道你们去过的所有地方
I know everywhere you been.
我所需要的就是知道
All I needed to hear was that it was you
是你把石头藏了起来
that hid the stone.
你都是装出来的吗
Was there ever a chance for you?
你弟弟可是很厉害的  狄格尔先生
Your brother's way beyond reach, Mr. Diggle.
现在全都结束了
It's all over now.
我正准备说这句话来着
Took the words right out of my mouth!
我需要祭献
I need to sacrifice.
还不够  你知道该怎么做的
Not enough. You know what to do.
[咒语]
Kanjigar septum vohnostrum.
我感觉好多了
Oh, I feel so much better.
我为你的兄弟们感到抱歉
Hey. I am sorry about your buddies,
但我需要鲜血补充能量
but omelets and eggs and all of that.
但我知道该如何补偿你们
But I know how to make it up to you, though.
谁想到外面散散步
Who wants to go for a walk outside?
安迪好像提过
Andy here might have mentioned
他哥哥约翰是为绿箭侠卖命的
that his brother John worked for the Green Arrow,
或者我该称呼他为奥利弗·奎恩
Or should I say Oliver Queen?
你瞧  我知道你们都在想些什么
Oh, oh, oh, see, I know what you're all thinking,
但不是  不是他告诉我的
But, no, he didn't tell me.
很容易就能顺藤摸瓜
It was really just a hop, skip, and a jump
摸出狄格尔
from the whole Diggle connection
跟你  你妹妹  还有你前女友的关系
to you to your little sister to your ex-girlfriend,
你来救那个小男孩威廉时
but when you came to rescue that boy William,
你脸上的那个表情  是父亲的表情
that look on your face, that was a father's look.
我当时就应该认出来的
I should have recognized it there and then.
我们得马上离开这里
We need to get out of here now.
耐心点
Patience.
我等这一刻等很久了
I've been waiting for this moment for a long time.
兰斯小姐  九个月前
Ms. Lance, 9 months ago,
我就向你爸爸保证过
I made your daddy a promise.
我告诉了他背叛我会有什么下场
I told him what I would do if he betrayed me.
射得真好
Impressive.
我刚刚讲到哪里了
Now where was I?
哦对了  我希望你帮我向你父亲
Oh, yeah. I want you to give your father a message
递个话
from me.
我想让你告诉他
I want you to tell him--unh!
我说到做到
I'm a man of my word.
没事的  没事的
Hey, hey. It's all right. It's ok.
看着我  你会没事的
Hey, hey. Look at me. You're gonna be all right.
你会没事的  挺住
You're gonna be all right. Come on.
帮帮忙  请过来帮帮忙
Help! Help in here, please!
快救她  求你了
You have to help her, please!
她失血过多
She's lost a lot of blood.
马上带急救车和创伤急救队过来
I need a crash cart and a trauma team in here stat!
-放开她  -什么
- Let her go. - What?
你放开她
I need you to let her go
我才能好好工作
so I can do my job.
快走吧
Now leave!
创伤急救队马上就到了
The trauma team will be in here any second,
她现在最不需要的就是马戏团在她身边
and the last thing she needs right now is a circus.
快走  快走
Go! Go.
你怎么学会
How do you know how to do this,
活埋一个人的
to bury a man alive?
你说得对  这座岛改变了你
You were right how this island changed you.
你还会看你那张照片吗
Do you still look at your picture?
她真漂亮
She's beautiful.
她是谁
Who is she?
她叫劳蕾尔·兰斯
Her name is Laurel Lance,
在这一切发生前  她是我的归属
and she was my home before all this.
我不知道看到我变成这样
I don't know what she'll think
她会怎么想
of the man I've become.
如果我没成功逃出这座岛
If I don't make it off this island,
你就去俄罗斯找我父母
you will go to Russia and find my parents
告诉他们我和瓦勒徳的遭遇
and tell them what happened to me and Vlad.
如果你没成功逃出去
If you don't make it,
我就去找劳蕾尔小姐
I will find this Laurel
告诉她你怎么救了我们
and tell her how you saved us all.
成交吗
Deal?
成交
Deal.
巴伦  我们得离开这里
Baron, we've got to get out of here.
没办法离开了
There is no getting out,
但你们死去
but with your deaths,
也许能让我活下来
I might yet just live.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
[咒语]
Kanjigar septum vohnostrum.
今日铁山监狱发生暴乱
Today's prison riot at Iron Heights
铁山监狱的暴乱和越狱事件
让整座城市人心惶惶
has left the city on edge.
洛佩滋  洛佩滋
Hey, Lopez, Lopez.
监狱里出什么事了
What happened at the, uh--at the prison?
你打晕了一名副队长
Uh, you punched out a lieutenant.
我知道  我是问在那之后
Yeah. I mean, after that.
他们阻止了那些犯人越狱吗
Did they keep those inmates from escaping?
他们人数太多了
Too many of them,
而且达克
and one--Darhk--
打伤了其中一人
he hurt one of them.
什么  他打伤了谁
What? What? Who--who'd he hurt?
治安维持者  黑金丝雀
The vigilantes. The Black Canary.
她好像伤得很严重
Supposedly, he hurt her real bad.
听着  我得离开这里  好吗
I--um, listen. Uh, I got to get out of here, all right?
这事真的很重要
It's--it's real important,
你可以帮我
so please get me, uh-- see if you can get
打个电话给派克副队吗
Lieutenant Pike on the phone.
他出去主持抓捕越狱犯人的工作了
He's out supervising the manhunt for the escaped prisoners.
你得给他打电话  行吗
You got to get him on the phone, all right,
因为我得跟他谈
because I got to talk to him,
而且得离开一小时
because I got to get out of here just for an hour.
我会自己回来的  行吗
I'm gonna surrender myself back in, all right?
没关系的  但只要
That's fine, but just--just
接通派克副队的电话  拜托了
get Lieutenant Pike on the phone, please.
劳蕾尔  她...
Laurel--is she--
劳蕾尔在做手术
Laurel's in surgery.
我也不知道
I don't know.
我一直想联系兰斯...
I've tried calling Lance, too, so...
达克怎么了
What happened with Darhk?
他和五十几个狱友逃走了
He's in the wind along with 50 or so inmates.
连同安迪
And Andy.
你警告了我  但我没听
You warned me, and I didn't listen.
我永远都不能原谅自己了
I'll never be able to forgive myself.
天啊
Oh, my god.
刚醒来
Just out of recovery.
她会好起来的
She's gonna be fine.
你们的朋友很坚强
She's a strong woman, your friend.
最坚强了
The strongest.
她一直要求见你们
She's been asking for you.
你们好啊
Hi.
你也好啊
Hey yourself.
达克有没有...
Did Darhk--
别操心他了
Don't worry about him.
想着怎样赶紧好起来吧
Just worry about getting better, ok?
我对我最后一晚的预想可不是这样的
It's not exactly how I wanted my last night to go.
这话什么意思
What are you talking about?
说来话长
It's a long story.
我本来打算不当黑金丝雀了
I was gonna give up being the Black Canary,
但我发现我做不到
but I realized I didn't know how I could
因为与你们并肩作战  铲奸除恶
because going out there and fighting alongside you guys,
让我内心感到生机
it's what makes me feel alive inside...
而且我真的好爱你们
And I love you guys so much.
我们也爱你
We love you.
我们也许该让你休息一下
We should probably let you get some rest.
我们就在外面  好吗
We'll be right outside, ok?
好的
Ok.
你也该休息一下
You should probably get some rest, too.
不行
No chance.
我得陪着你
I'm gonna stay right here.
我衣服左口袋有东西
There's... something in my left pouch.
能拿给我吗
Will you bring it to me?
好
Yeah.
-要我打开吗  -嗯
- May I? - Yeah.
你一直留着吗
You kept this?
没错
Yeah.
为了怀念一下
Just a little reminder
我们那段简简单单的
of when things were simpler
时光
for us,
我们曾经的时光
The way we used to be.
我很高兴你找到了费利西蒂
I'm really glad that you found Felicity,
我也希望你和她重归于好
and I hope you find your way back to her,
还有  奥利  我知道我不是你一生挚爱
and, Ollie, I know that I am not the love of your life...
但你一直是我的一生挚爱
But you will always be the love of mine.
你为什么跟我说这些
Why are you telling me this?
为什么现在说
Why now?
因为今晚提醒了我们...
Because tonight it was just a reminder that...
一切皆有可能
anything can happen,
所以我需要你答应我一些事
which is why I need you to promise me something.
我刚与兰斯队长通完电话
I just got off the phone with Captain Lance.
他在路上了  我告诉他劳蕾尔很好
He's on his way. I--I told him that she's doing fine.
借过
Out of the way!
有栓塞  给我五千单位的肝素
Embolism. I need 5,000 units of heparin bolus!
怎么回事
What happened?
不知道  她刚才还好好的
Uh, I--I don't know. She was fine.
除颤板
Paddles!
充电中  两百
Charging. 200.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Clear? -  Clear.
没反应
Nothing.
给她输氧
Let's bag her.
马上打开输氧管
Open up right away.
加油啊  挺住
Come on. Come on.
血氧含量下降30%  还在下降
Blood lost 30%, dropping.
加油
Come on!
她要不行了
She's closed.
加油
Come on.
无反应
No response.
死亡时间  十一点五十九分
Time of death 11:59.